Guide to the George Rust papers, 1808-1879 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
George Rust papers 1808-1879
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Rust, George, 1788-1857
3.5 Linear Feet Approx. 3,343 Items
Businessman, militia officer, and Virginia state legislator, of Baltimore, Maryland, and Leesburg, Virginia.
Collection houses correspondence and other papers of George Rust and of his family, relating to Rust's legislative career, his work on behalf of the Jacksonian Democrats, his investment activities in Maryland and Virginia banks and mercantile firms, and his association with the Virginia militia. Includes letters from members of the family in other sections of the United States.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The George Rust papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1957.
Collection Overview
Correspondence and other papers of Rust and of his family, relating to Rust's legislative career, his work on behalf of the Jacksonian Democrats, his investment activities in Maryland and Virginia banks and mercantile firms, and his association with the Virginia militia. Includes letters from members of the family in other sections of the U.S.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Democratic Party (U.S.)
Banks and banking -- Southern States
Migration, Internal -- United States
Maryland -- Economic conditions
Politicians -- Virginia -- Correspondence
United States -- Politics and government -- 1815-1861
Virginia. Militia
Virginia -- Economic conditions
Virginia -- Politics and government -- 1775-1865
Contents of Collection
- George Rust papers, 1808-1879 and undated, (7 boxes)
  - Correspondence, 1808-1855 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1856-1879 (Box 2)
  - Bills and receipts, 1800s-1830s (Box 3)
  - Bills and receipts, 1840s (Box 4)
  - Bills and receipts, 1840s-1850s (Box 5)
  - Bills and receipts, 1850s (Box 6)
  - Bills and receipts, 1850s-1866 and undated (Box 7)
  - Legal papers, 1813-1858 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous papers (Box 7)
  - Printed material and volumes (Box 7)